

IRENE AUÑÓN

BILINGUAL TRANSLATOR (ENGLISH/SPANISH)

ABOUT ME

Professional bilingual teacher with extensive experience in translation and localization (ES>EN and EN>ES) seeking to focus their career on the video game and audiovisual sectors.

Over a decade of experience working in the filmmaking industry as an assistant director, script supervisor, and director.

Video game enthusiast, from bigger productions, such as Uncharted and Assassins Creed, to small indie games, such as Firewatch and Dwarf Fortress to smaller indie titles.

LANGUAGES

SPANISH ENGLISH ITALIAN FRENCH



IT TOOLS

Microsoft Office, LibreOffice, Google Drive, Smartcat and other CAT tools Subtitle Workshop, Jubler Photoshop, Adobe Premiere, etc.

CONTACT

ireneenglish.com ireneaunion.com

irene@ireneenglish.com +34 610 40 66 25

EXPERIENCE

TRANSLATION, LOCATIZATION AND SUBTITLING ES>EN Freelance | Oct 2017 - Present

- Shortfilm "Aquel No Era Yo" "That Wasn't Me"
 - Nominated for THE OSCARS Academy Awards in 2014
- Shortfilms, scripts, spots, documentaries
 - Numerous audiovisual projects.
- Video game "Chronicles of Elyria" City of Cartago
 - Information about the city, its history, its government, its politics, and all the key elements the player needs to know.
- Websites, blogs and online articles.
 - Filmmakers' websites, customer service, teaching and education, etc.
 - Related to the audiovisual/filmmaking industry. Blogs about relationships, sexuality, self-improvement and femininity.
- School curriculum plans and educational/teaching materials
 - Physical Education, health, grammar, linguistics, etc.

TRANSLATION, LOCATIZATION AND SUBTITLING EN>ES Freelance | Oct 2017 - Present

- Transcribing, subtitling and semantic labeling for online lectures and webinars for the accesibility program at UNED.
 - Winner of the "Volunteer of the year 2015" prize granted by UNED and VODAFONE Foundation.
- Legal and property administration and management documents.

LANGUAGE TEACHER - ENGLISH AND SPANISH Freelance | Oct 2014 - Present

- All ages and levels (A1-C2).
- Companies and institutions: ¡HOLA! (Hello! Magazine), Mutuapesca, law firms, San Miguel Arcángel School.

INDEPENDENT FILMMAKER

Freelance | Oct 2010 - Present

- Experience as: 1st Assistant Director, Script Supervisor, Director.
- National and international projects.

EDUCATION

 MASTER'S DEGREE IN TEACHER TRAINING IN COMPULSORY SECONDARY AND UPPER SECONDARY SCHOOL EDUCATION, VOCATIONAL TRAINING AND FOREIGN LANGUAGE TEACHING

Universidad Rey Juan Carlos | 2017 - 2018

 B.A. IN ENGLISH PHILOLOGY - ENGLISH STUDIES: LANGUAGE, LITERATURE AND CULTURE

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia (UNED)| 2012 - 2016

- DEGREE IN DIRECTING FOR FILM AND TV
 Instituto del Cine de Madrid | 2010-2013 (Madrid Film Institute)
- COURSE ON VOICE-OVER ACTING, SPEECH AND DUBBING Instituto del Cine de Madrid | 2011 (Madrid Film Institute)